[robotic, upbeat music]
-[man grunts]
-[clatters]
- [woman] [moaning] No, no! No!
No, no, please! [screams]
Oh, please. No, no, no!
[screams]
[robotic, upbeat music
continues]
-[man] Once more,
they will replenish themselves.
[indistinct]
The power of their source.
The Christian...
The Christian.
The power of their source.
[upbeat music continues]
-[AI on phone]
Incoming call from Mandy.
-Hello?
-[Mandy] Hey, yeah, you called?
-Hey.
-[Mandy] Hi.
-Hey, so, uh, Aaron said
that you're picking him up
from the game,
so I figured I'd drop him off
if that works.
-[Mandy]
I'll be coming from a meeting,
so, you know, it'd be nice
if you could make it there too,
show a little support.
-Look, it's my last day
on the job.
The whole point
of this early retirement
is so that I could spend
more time with him and you.
Just--just let me finish this--
-[Mandy] Can you remind Aaron
about his socks?
-His socks?
Yeah, sure.
-[Mandy] Great.
[foreboding music]
[fridge door creaks open]
[clanking]
-[Shaw] Hey, morning, champ.
You're up early.
-[Aaron] Yeah. Coach wants us
ready for the big game today.
-Yeah, well, I'm gonna do
everything I can to be there.
-Sounds familiar.
-Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
I'm doing everything...
Let me make you some breakfast.
-Never before practice.
-Well, I didn't realize you guys
practiced on game night.
-Yeah, there's a lot
that you don't realize, Dad.
[distant dog barking]
-Well, that's all going
to change now, okay?
Is he starting you today?
-Yeah.
-Yeah? Thatta boy.
[laughing] Thatta boy.
-Why are you being weird?
-I'm--I'm just excited,
that's all.
Look, I know that it's been
tough since Mom moved out,
splitting time between—
-Can we not do this now? Please?
-Yeah. Yeah,
whenever you're ready.
I'll shower up
and I'll take you to school.
-I'm 16, Dad.
I can get myself to school.
-Hey...
Your mom mentioned
something about socks.
You know what she meant?
-[Aaron] Yeah.
-Okay. Maybe drop the attitude.
-Bye, Dad.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
[unsettling piano notes]
[door closes]
[unsettling music]
Morning, Keyes.
-Morning.
-Just hanging out
by yourself down here?
-[Keyes] Yeah.
-Yeah?
-Wanted you to have your coffee.
-Oh, that's very sweet of you.
Wouldn't happen to be
a surprise party in there,
would there?
-Just act surprised.
-[Shaw] [laughs]
I'll try my best.
-Surprise! [applauding]
-[laughs] Thank you all.
Thank you.
-Well, maybe this
will fix things at home.
And if not, I know a
pretty good divorce attorney.
-[laughs] You know what,
you always say
the sweetest things, Deacon.
-It's just my
natural disposition, you know.
-This one.
-It's been fun, Sloan.
-All right,
so first off, everyone,
I want to thank this man
for 20 years plus of service
to this department.
Let's give it up for him.
-[clapping] Woo!
-Thank you.
Thank you.
-And on behalf of the city,
we'd like to give you
this fine-looking pen.
Caitlin, would you get in here,
please?
Just one quick photo op,
if you don't mind,
Detective Shaw.
Right here.
-One, two, three.
[mouths] Perfect.
-There you go.
-You shouldn't have.
Thank you.
-Yeah, well... uh, also,
I couldn't help
overhearing you
talking to Deacon
and him giving you advice.
So first off, let me tell you,
as a man who's been married
almost 20 years,
you tell her you love her...
-[Shaw] Hm.
-...you buy her gifts,
you give her flowers,
and the number one thing you
don't do is listen to Deacon.
-[laughter]
-Don't worry, Mayor,
I won't--I won't.
Thank you for the pen.
-All right. All right.
Congratulations.
-Mayor Richards, you mind if I
have a moment alone with Shaw?
-He's all yours, Captain.
-Thank you all.
Now get back to work,
would you?
-[man] Yeah.
Nice pants.
-Thank you.
-I never thought
I'd see the day.
-You're not gonna get all soft
on me now, are you, Haas?
Give me a speech?
-All jokes aside,
you were one of the best...
besides me.
-[laughs]
I appreciate that.
-So what are your plans now?
What does the future hold
for the big detective?
-I don't know, Captain.
I just, you know,
I want to spend as much time
with my kid as I can
before he heads off to college.
So I was hoping
to finish the paperwork up
on the Carter case
so I could head
over to his game.
It's been a while.
-Go home, and I have Deacon
finish the work for you.
-I heard that.
-Are you sure?
I just got here.
-That's an order.
Go to Aaron's game before
something stupid happens.
I take your badge
at the end of the day.
You can come back then.
-Okay. Thank you.
It's been a pleasure, Haas.
[upbeat music]
[distant siren wailing]
[chuckling]
♪ Runnin' in the story
of my life ♪
♪ [indistinct rap] ♪
♪ And everyday that I try ♪
♪ Can never do nothing right ♪
♪ And every day passes by
so fast, another one coming ♪
♪ And every day that I live
is another day that I'm living ♪
♪ Runnin' in the story
of my life ♪
♪ [indistinct] and every day
that I try ♪
♪ Can never do nothing right ♪
♪ And every day passes by so
fast, another one coming ♪
♪ And every day that I live is
another day that I'm living ♪
♪ Runnin' in the story
of my life ♪
♪ Try, yeah ♪
♪ I'm trying to
(Yeah, yeah) ♪
♪ To live carefree ♪
-Unless your cat
is on a murdering rampage,
we only deal with humans here.
Good luck.
You can file this under people
who love their pets too much.
-[officer] [chuckles]
Yes, Detective.
-After you.
Hi. I'd like to report a murder.
[laughs]
-Show me your hands.
Take your right hand
out of your pocket.
-You gotta be more
convincing than that.
-Right hand
out of your pocket, now!
-See, that's better.
-Drop the knife.
Drop it.
[knife clanks]
Turn around
and face away from me.
Do it.
-Now we're getting somewhere.
[laughs]
[knife slides]
-Get down on your knees.
Put your hands on your head.
-Boo! [grunts]
-[officer] Stop resisting.
-Now, now. See,
this is the response we expect
[laughs]
out of our police force.
[foreboding music]
-All right, kid.
Let's start from the top.
-I'm only talking
to Detective Shaw.
-Detective Shaw isn't here.
-Well, then you better
get him here.
♪ Come and save me
[indistinct] ♪
♪ It's right on the street ♪
♪ I'm gonna take you
for a ride ♪
♪ In my Lincoln Continental ♪
♪ [indistinct] right ones ♪
♪ Check it out and see ♪
♪ Wanna take you for a ride ♪
♪ In my Lincoln Continental ♪
[music stops]
[phone ringing]
-Yeah?
- [Keyes] It's me.
-Yeah, I know.
Couldn't wait an hour, huh?
-[exhales] We've got a kid here.
There's blood.
He's asking for you.
Won't say a word
to anyone else.
-Hi, Detective.
-Is that him?
-[Keyes] Yep.
-You got a name, age?
-[Keyes] Nothin'.
-All right. Give me--
give me ten minutes.
-As far as I can tell,
he'll wait.
[pensive music]
-Well, that was
a quick retirement.
-Yeah. Where is he?
-Down the viewing room.
Come on.
[security door buzzes]
[door hinges creak closes]
-Oh, this better be good, Haas.
-I'm gonna follow up
with these labs,
find out whose blood that is.
-Anything?
-Nothing.
-Do you recognize him?
-No. Fingerprints?
-Tried. Get this,
kid's fingertips, all burned.
Couldn't get a clean print.
-All right.
[security door buzzes, opens]
-[laughs]
-So I hear you wanted
to talk to me?
-Yes, I very much do,
Detective Shaw.
I have so much
pertinent information for you
to write down on your notepad.
-Okay, yeah. [coughs]
Yeah, we'll get to that.
Um, let's start
with the basics.
Can I get your name, please?
-You already know my name.
-Uh, no, I don't.
-Yes, you do.
-No, I don't.
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
Uh, your age...
-[exhales]
-Look, if you're a minor,
you need to be accompanied
by an adult.
-[the kid] You don't have
to worry about that.
-[Shaw]
What do I have to worry about?
-Everything that I'm trying
to tell you.
-Well, there is a murder, right?
-Oh yeah, but the blood's
on your hands. [sniffles]
-The blood's on my hands.
-Mm-hmm.
Well, you and your ilk.
-My ilk?
-[chuckles] They know.
-Okay. What do they know?
Oh, I'm sorry. Am I...
am I getting ahead of you?
-Don't patronize me.
-You know what, let's talk
about the murder. Okay?
-Not the murder. Them.
-Them, the--the people
of my ilk.
-[the kid] Yes.
-Right.
-Exactly.
Because of who you are,
people listen to you, right?
You would say that?
People listen to you,
but because of who I am,
no one listens to me.
-I'm listening.
-Yeah, now you're listening.
Are we that different?
Would you say that my word
is worth less somehow?
Are we that dissimilar?
-Probably.
-Hmm.
-I don't know you,
and you don't know me, so...
-Well, no, no.
I know enough about you.
[clears throat]
I know that you're not perfect,
and we are humans,
so we make mistakes.
And sometimes those mistakes
come back to haunt us.
-I guess.
-Today you are going
to be haunted.
[dramatic music]
[security door buzzes, opens]
-Shaw, you got a minute?
-Yeah.
-[laughs] Right on time.
See you soon.
-All right, Deacon. Look,
if you're gonna come in there--
-We got the results of the blood
on the kid.
Three vics, human.
One A positive, one A negative,
and one B positive.
We got a serial killer.
-No, we may have
a serial killer.
-[scoffs]
Let me at this kid.
I'll get him to talk.
-All right,
the kid has to talk to me.
Let me see
where I get with him.
Now, if you want to sit in there
and observe silently, fine.
Otherwise, I do the talking,
you understand?
[security door buzzes, opens]
Well, looks like we have
some new information--
-I see you brought
Deputy Cocksucker?
[dramatic sting]
-Excuse me, asshole?
-Let it go, Detective.
Just let it go.
-Who did you kill?
I want names now!
No, right now!
[grunting]
-Hey! Hey!
Get in here!
Put him in here!
[overlapping chatter]
-[female officer] Get back!
-Call the medic! Now!
Get out! Medic!
[tense music]
-Brother,
don't you die on me.
Partners for life, remember?
Cap?
-Go on.
Go with your brother.
-What the hell happened here?
-Trying to find out, sir.
-Trying? Trying's
not good enough, Detective.
How does this happen
in our precinct, Captain?
-I understand your frustration,
but there's procedure.
-I don't give a damn
about your procedure.
He just stabbed a cop.
-Why don't you calm down?
I got to get ahead of this.
[distant radio chatter]
[train honking]
-Is it me,
or does he seem too calm?
-The precinct is now
an active crime scene.
Press is gathering,
I need
to call Deacon's wife.
-How the hell
do you explain this?
-I don't know.
[security door buzzes, opens]
-Where's that son of a bitch?
Move out of the way!
Move out of the way, assholes!
-Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What's going on?
-I'll tell you exactly
what's going on.
That piece of shit
killed my brother.
-What?
-These jackasses
are trying to protect him.
-Wait, wait, he killed him?
-Deacon's dead.
-Oh shit.
-Just give me five minutes,
Shaw.
Come on, just five minutes.
Come on!
-Sloan, you know
that I can't let you do that.
-You going to stop me?
-I--I get it. I get it,
and I'm sorry to hear
about your brother,
but this is too personal
for you now.
You need to calm down
and let me do my job.
-This kid just graduated
from suspect to cop killer.
It ends now, Shaw.
-Guys, hold him back, please.
-You're gonna protect
a cop killer?
Really?
Don't touch--don't touch me!
-Whose side are you on, Shaw?
-The right side.
-[Sloan] This isn't over!
-Come on. Let's go.
[security door buzzes, opens]
-Oh, Shaw. Thank God.
I have worked up
a very big appetite.
I'm starving.
-That man had a family.
And now he's dead.
So we have everything
we need to put you away.
-I gave you everything you need
to put me away.
I gave it to you.
You know what
I don't have, though,
and I really need,
is some chips.
I saw that we passed
a vending machine on the way in,
and I didn't get a chance
to eat breakfast this morning.
-You want some chips?
-I'm really hungry.
-Tell me about the murder.
-Which one?
-There's more than one?
-Oh...Come on,
you already knew that.
It's not that easy.
There are steps.
[phone vibrating, ringing]
-Shit.
-[the kid] Answer it.
-Shut up.
Yeah.
-[Mandy] Do you have Aaron?
-What? No.
Isn't he in school?
-He's not at school.
-[Mandy] He's not at school.
They called me to say
he never showed up.
-[cackles]
-Well, I--I'm sure he's fine.
I'll--I'll find him
and I'll give you a call back.
-[Mandy] Wait, Matt, hold on.
Wait--
-Trouble with the family?
I can help you.
[laughs] Call him.
[phone keys beeping]
[phone trilling]
- [the kid's voice]
Hi, you've reached
the personal voicemail box
of Aaron Shaw.
He's not able to come
to the phone right now.
He's in a bit of a pickle,
so hopefully he'll call you back
within 10 hours.
-What did you do with my son?
-I buried him...alive.
-Bullshit.
-I can show you.
I don't have my phone,
so I'd need yours.
Yeah.
[dramatic music]
[the kid cackles]
-What--what--what's
the timer for?
-I'm glad that you asked.
The timer is telling you
that he has less than nine hours
of oxygen left
before he loses consciousness,
and then, well...
he'll die, so...
[dramatic, tense music]
[choking]
-Where is he?
-[the kid] You kill me,
you kill him.
-What do you want?
What do you want?!
-[coughs] What do I want?
I want you to do your job
before you retire!
There are three murders
that I need you to solve,
and then I'll tell you
where your son is.
I would start
by finding his phone.
That'll lead you
to the first case.
And don't bring your
stupid friends into this.
This is between you and me.
Now go. Go.
Tick-tock, tick-tock.
[panting]
[security door buzzes, opens]
-[Haas]
What did he say to you, Shaw?
-Give me--just give me
a few minutes.
Just give me a minute
with the guy.
Come on, stop.
-What are you gonna do, Sloan?
You gonna beat him up?
With cameras
and witnesses everywhere?
You're going to throw
your whole goddamn career
down the toilet.
Go home.
Go home!
Don't let him in there.
-[strains] Stop it!
[security door buzzes, opens]
-Hey, you okay?
-Uh, I'm gonna need your help,
okay?
-Anything. What do you need?
-I--I can't tell you right now.
I just need to know
that you're with me, okay?
-Always.
-Keep your phone on
and don't tell anybody
that I left.
[overlapping chatter]
-All right, settle down, please.
Firstly, I want
to send my deepest condolences
to the entire Deacon family,
and I want them to know
that we will not stop
until this killer
is brought to justice.
And when I ran for mayor,
I made a pledge
to you good people
that I would not only
keep my family safe,
but yours too.
And that includes the brave men
and women in blue
who serve us every single day.
Now, we lost one
of our own here.
This one's personal.
[overlapping chatter]
One at a time,
one at a time. Go ahead.
-What do you have to say
about the recent allegations?
-These are not allegations,
all right?
We caught a kid red-handed
in the station with a knife.
We're going to prosecute,
and I'm going to put this guy
away for life.
[overlapping chatter]
-[panting]
Oh, shit.
[phone ringing]
Hey.
-[Mandy] Did you find him?
-I can't really get into it
right now, but yes,
I'm--I'm gonna find him.
-[Mandy]
You're freaking me out, Matt.
Where's my son?
-Look, we have a kid in holding
and--and...and he took him.
-[Mandy] He took Aaron?
What do you...what do you mean?
-I will give you an update
as soon as I have one, okay?
I promise you,
I'm gonna tell you--
-[Mandy] You find my son, Matt.
-I will find him. I promise.
[car engine starts]
[car engine revs]
[pensive music]
[phone beeping]
Police!
Police! Coming in!
[phone beeping]
[phone beeps]
[suspenseful music]
[panting]
[door hinges creak]
[whispers] Is a virtue.
[dramatic, tense music]
[gasping]
[high-pitched ringing]
[dramatic sting]
[panting]
[foreboding music]
-[indistinct]
What are you doing here?
[screaming]
[foreboding music intensifies]
[screams, grunts]
[foreboding music fades]
[breathes weakly]
[screaming in pain]
-[panting]
[panting]
Sycamore. [panting]
[dramatic, tense music]
[phone keys beeping]
[phone vibrating]
-Yeah.
-The kid has Aaron somewhere.
-Shit.
I'm so sorry, Matt.
-Let me bring this to Haas.
He can help.
-No, not yet.
I told Mandy,
but no one else can know.
I need a favor.
[security door buzzes, opens]
[distant radio chatter]
-Are those for me?
-They're from Detective Shaw.
He filled me in.
I'm guessing the woman you
killed wasn't a good listener?
-No, she was not.
-The kid in the photos
with the face scratched,
is that you?
Another metaphor?
Victim was Victoria Hewitt.
-[the kid crunching]
-Was she your social worker?
-She was, and she wasn't
a very good one at that.
Tell me, Detective Shaw,
do you like my game?
-You think this is a game?
-It is a game.
And I know he's on the phone.
Hello, Detective Shaw.
[phone beeps]
-You're on speaker, Shaw.
-Shaw, did you find the clues?
[laughs]
-[Shaw] Where's my son?
Where is he?!
-I told you,
this is the first murder.
There are three in total.
You have under eight hours
before your son loses oxygen.
I'm getting so tired of you
trying to bully
the information out of me.
Follow the clues like
a real detective would!
-What is this about?
-Retribution.
These chips are fucking stale.
[chip thumps]
[door thumps]
[train honking]
[car revving]
-[GPS AI] In 100 feet, your
destination will be on the left.
[soft, suspenseful music]
[knocks on door]
-Hello!
[door creaks open]
[soft, suspenseful
music continues]
[panting]
[door creaks open]
[dramatic sting]
-No. [groaning]
[block slides]
[dramatic, suspenseful music]
[body thuds]
-[panting]
-[woman screaming, echoes]
[intense music]
-Ah!
[straining]
-[grunts]
[knife clanks]
-[grunting in pain]
-[groans]
-[grunts]
[foreboding music]
[choking]
-[panting]
[dramatic sting]
[gasps, groans]
[strains]
[strains] [panting]
[panting]
[door thumps]
-[Keyes] Did you find him?
-No, no.
I--I found another victim.
-How bad?
-It--it--it's bad.
What if I can't find him?
What if...
what if I get there
and it's too late?
-Nope, no way.
Aaron's alive.
The kid said you had 10 hours.
-Well, it's seven hours,
20 minutes now.
-Get moving.
You know where you're going?
-Yeah.
-[Keyes] Send me the information
about this one.
-Okay, anything new on the kid?
-We got the
social worker's records,
but she had 150 cases.
Captain Haas
has a couple detectives
looking into it, but--
-Well, it's a long shot.
-Yeah. The kid in the photo...
we're talking abuse
over years, right?
-Yeah, Deacon...
Deacon handled all crimes
against children,
so if there's anything,
it's gonna be in his files.
-Copy that. Matt?
-[Shaw] What?
-What does any of this have
to do with you?
-I have no idea.
[door open, closes]
-You wanted to see me?
-[Haas]
Keyes, give me your phone.
-[Keyes] My phone?
-Yeah. Now.
[phone beeps]
[dramatic music]
[car revs]
[phone beeps]
-[Shaw] Hey.
-[Mandy] Matt, where is he?
-Mandy,
I'm doing everything I can.
You gotta trust me.
-[Mandy] Trust you?
Matt, my son is in danger!
-Our--it's our son!
I'm not gonna stop
until I find him.
Do you understand me?
Look, Mandy, I gotta--
I know you're scared, okay?
I know you're scared,
but we are gonna be okay.
All right? I gotta go. Bye.
Did you get
an identity on him?
-Whose identity, Shaw?
-I'm sorry,
he made me.
-Hey, he's paying back
some kind of debt
and you are on his list.
You need to come in now.
What does he have on you?
-Goddamn it, Captain, just--
-No, Detective.
Or it will be your badge.
-My--I'm retired, remember?
-Not for another five hours.
-This is getting
way out of hand.
You have to tell him.
-Wait, tell me what?
You need to come in right now.
-[Keyes] You gotta let
some people in, Shaw.
You can't do it
all yourself.
-He took my son.
What if it was your kid, Haas?
What if somebody took Nate?
You would do everything
in your power to get him back.
Now, I am asking you
for a little more time.
I'm not asking for much, but--
-Is that Shaw?
I want him here now.
-Haas, you owe me this.
-All right, keep going, but I'm
putting you on a tight leash.
-Keep going?
Did you just hear what I said?
Bring him in now,
or it's your badge too, Captain.
-Haas.
-Do what you gotta do,
then get your ass back here.
-[Shaw] Understood.
[car revving]
[distant crows cawing]
[car door thumps]
-I'll call you back.
-Seventeen sixty-three
Stockton Ave.
-Ah.Daniella Whitby, 35.
Find out everything you can.
-[Keyes] Got it.
[door thumps]
[floor creaking]
[flies buzzing]
[dramatic sting]
[floor creaking]
-[gagging]
[panting]
[dramatic sting]
[ominous music]
-[woman screams, echoes]
-Well, look who it is.
Miss me?
[groans]
[grunts]
[door latch clicks]
[grunts, screams]
[groaning]
No!
No, no, no, please! [screams]
[scream, echoes]
[groaning]
[skull cracks]
[foreboding music]
[wet squelch]
-Jesus Christ.
[panting] Gotcha.
[dramatic music swells, stops]
[groans]
[camera shutter clicks]
[phone keys beeping]
[phone pings]
[telephone ringing]
-This is Haas.
-Hey. I 'm headed over
to Woodington High right now.
Have a unit meet me there.
-Who are we going after?
-I just sent you a photo.
Try to find out who she is.
-Shaw, tell me this one
is alive.
-I think we finally
found somebody
who's not on the hit list.
[somber music]
[car engine starts, revs]
[crow cawing]
[car door thumps]
How you doing, Officer Biss?
Thanks.
Do you know who this is?
-This is Jackson Adams.
He was in my Spanish class.
He...he died recently.
-How?
-He killed himself.
He was a great kid.
I...I really enjoyed
having him in my class.
-And--and what about
the other boy?
-AJ Adams, his brother.
He's about five years older.
They were tight,
like real brothers.
AJ was always very protective
of Jackson.
-And why did--
why did Jackson killed himself?
-I don't know.
Maybe because he couldn't take
the abuse anymore.
Jackson came in
with a broken collarbone
a month after he got
the cast off his arm.
I reported Daniella,
his foster mom,
several times to the police.
They said they
were handling it.
-Do you remember any names?
-A detective.
I have his card somewhere.
-Okay, and--and--and tell me
more about AJ.
-Like I said, he...he was
a lot older than Jackson.
He was a very smart kid.
I--I remember thinking
he was one of the smartest
I ever taught.
Jackson had it bad,
but AJ...he had it way worse.
He just never said
anything about it.
He was the reason why I knew
to look for signs in Jackson.
Not that I had
to look any harder.
These kids, they were
beaten pretty badly.
-Did you--did you report
any of this?
-Of course I did.
You think I didn't?
-No, no, no.
I...I believe you,
but I'm just wondering,
was there anything wrong
with AJ?
-He was quiet, kept to himself,
except when it came to Jackson.
That's the only thing
that ever got him worked up.
-Do you think it's possible
that AJ
could be capable of murder?
-Well, with
the psychological trauma
on top of the physical abuse--
-That's a perfect storm.
-Yeah. Here, I found it.
Um...Detective Deacon.
-Oh my God.
Thank you.
[pensive music]
[car engine revs]
[overlapping chatter]
-What do you need?
-Nothing. Thank you.
-We're going to find Aaron.
I promise.
[overlapping chatter]
-Shaw! Sit down now.
-You called in SWAT?
-[Haas] Have you seen
what's going on out there?
-I want this kid moved.
I want him moved right now.
-We're ready to move him.
-No, you can't.
-We sure as shit can.
I don't take orders from you.
-I'm not done with him yet.
-He's ain't safe here, Shaw.
-I said I want the kid moved.
-He kidnapped my son!
-What?
-Yes. I've been running around
all morning.
Three murders, all staged,
and I still don't know why.
Or...or where my son is.
I--I need more time.
-You got 20 minutes.
-Thank you.
-Thanks, Haas.
Twenty minutes, Shaw.
He said 20 minutes.
-[officer] All right.
Hurry. Twenty minutes.
-Let's go, everyone.
Back to work.
[security buzzes, opens]
-I'm right behind you.
-Kill the cameras.
You have my attention.
-Did you go to the school?
-[Shaw] I did.
-And how is Maria? [sniffles]
She always had
a soft spot for me.
-Not that soft.
She always said there
was something wrong with you.
-Ow, my heart!
Is that supposed to hurt?
-Not as much as Jackson's death,
I suspect.
-[laughing] Touché.
-You know, I could say
the same about you, AJ.
Everyone thought you
killed Deacon for no reason,
but I have a sneaky feeling that
that was all planned, right?
-[laughing] I almost thought
he wasn't gonna come at me.
-Everything was planned?
-Yes.
-Did they really have
to die that way,
you sick son of a bitch?
-You tell me.
-Well, Daniela was cruel.
I saw the photos.
It was awful.
So I guess
I can understand that one.
But the--the--the rest of them?
-You don't even know
the half of it, Shaw.
-The other two,
the social worker
and the guy that worked
at the Big Brother house,
that was too much.
-Was it?
-Yeah, it was.
-I sent countless complaints.
Countless.
She ignored every one.
She's the reason Jackson's dead!
-So the guy
at the Big Brother house,
how long did you
actually know him?
-Long enough for him to know.
-And it was enough for you
to hang him
and cut his goddamn tongue out?
-I didn't hang him.
You hung him!
When you opened the door
and you knocked over the 2x4.
So how does that feel, Shaw?
Seeing someone die because
you neglected to pay attention?
Jackson and I weren't just
neglected by our foster mother.
No, she didn't just forget
to feed us once or twice.
This was institutional.
In fact, it was enforced.
They took Jackson every week.
Every--fuck.
[sobs]
And every time he would
come back with more bruises,
just like me.
-Look, I get it.
You and Jackson were
screwed over by the system.
I, I totally understand that.
But my son... my son had nothing
to do with any of this.
Where is Aaron?
Where is he?
-Aaron?
You neglected Aaron too,
from what he says.
Married to his job,
how cliché.
You couldn't even go
to one of his ball games.
He cried like a bitch,
and he didn't even think
to call out your name.
[choking] You going
to do this again?
-I'm not going to ask you again.
Where's my son?
-I buried him.
Not much time left.
-Tell me where he is.
Where is he?!
-Now, we can get there
before he runs out of oxygen.
We have to go together.
-We?
-[coughs]
-What do you mean “we”?
-You think this is over,
don't you?
This isn't over.
I know you want to see him.
We're going to go together,
and I'll show you.
Otherwise, he's dead.
[panting]
[security door buzzes]
[spits]
[door slams]
-Ready to go, Captain.
-Hey, I--I need
to take the kid with me.
-Excuse me?
-He won't tell me where he is,
so he has to show me.
-Well, that's not gonna happen.
-Hell no.
-Goddamn it.
He buried him alive.
-Jesus.
-And he's almost out of oxygen,
so I need--I need--I need
to take the kid with me now.
Now!
-I have an idea.
[security door buzzes]
-You put these on.
[handcuffs clicking]
-I ain't wearing those.
And I have all day.
Aaron doesn't.
-Don't worry,
I'm not gonna lock 'em.
Hurry up.
[drone beeping]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[car revs]
[dramatic music]
[sniper clicks]
-[man] Time to roll out.
Let's move!
[car door slams]
[dramatic music]
[distant car revs]
[sirens wailing]
[drone whirring]
[sirens wailing continues]
-[groans]
Thank you, Detective.
-All right, you ready?
-Absolutely.
-All right, SWAT's
gonna lose us
while we're transferring you.
It's not a lot of time,
but it's enough.
-Better be.
-And he's here to make sure
you don't torture Aaron's
whereabouts out of me.
-Something like that.
-Is that what you want to do?
Torture me? [laughs]
-Don't answer that.
[dramatic music continues]
-Which way am I going?
-Turn right.
-[man] Car 2, come in.
Car 2.
-Car 2, go ahead.
-[man] Car 2, we lost visual
on the lead car.
Do you have a visual?
-We do.
-[man] And?
-I, uh, can't...hear you.
You're breaking up.
-What are you doing?
-We gotta let them
get ahead of us.
-What?
-Just a minute or two.
-Detective,
are you giving me an order?
-I'm asking. Please.
[tense music]
-Which way?
Which way?!
-Left.
-Why murder, AJ? Huh?
I know these people did terrible
things, but...but murder?
-I tried doing it your way.
Several times, in fact.
It didn't work.
-Yeah, well, killing
isn't usually the next step.
-I have your attention now,
don't I?
-Not every kid who was abused
turns to murder.
-You don't know
what they did to us.
Turn right.
-Who's they, huh?
Are there more?
-We weren't alone.
-What aren't you telling me?
Hey, what aren't
you telling me?
What did they do to you?
What did they do to you?!
[upbeat music]
-They made us fight.
[overlapping cheering]
[punch thrown]
-[AJ's voice]
Whenever they got bored...
an underage fight club.
[overlapping grunting]
These vultures put us in a ring
till only one of us
was left standing.
-[man] Finish him!
-[AJ's voice] Now, if we won,
we'd get certain privileges.
[grunts]
[groaning]
[overlapping cheering]
[grunts]
[AJ's voice] But if we lost...
probably in the medical room
for a week.
-[opponent grunts]
-[AJ's voice] Or worse...
[overlapping cheering]
[strains]
...dead.
[upbeat music]
-Jesus. But it still doesn't
excuse what you did.
And my son had nothing
to do with this.
-You don't get it.
This is bigger than us.
I'm just the tip
of the iceberg, Shaw.
Cops on the take,
and it goes all the way
to the top.
The big donor.
-What big donor?
[phone ringing]
[car tires screech, crashes]
[high-pitched ringing]
[groans]
[coughs, echoes]
Sloan. Sloan!
Drop it! Drop it!
-Stay in the car.
This is almost over.
-Drop it.
[gun fired]
-[Sloan grunts]
-[Shaw] Hey!
-[Sloan grunting in pain]
Son of a bitch, you shot me!
-Just keep pressure on it.
You'll thank me later.
-You have no idea.
This is bigger
than both of us.
-Officer down on the corner
of Capitol and Leake.
Send a paramedic.
-[grunts]
-[groans]
AJ! AJ! Where is he?
Where's my son?
-There's one more mystery
to solve, Shaw.
-No! I am done!
I did everything
you asked me to do!
-Shut up! You're so close,
and he's only got minutes
left of air,
so you better choose
your questions carefully.
-I figured out
the social worker.
I figured out your mom.
-Foster mother.
-The BSA guy.
The--the ex-boyfriend.
I don't get that one.
-What do you mean?
I reported the fighting to him,
and then Daniella claimed
that I was a kid acting up.
And because she is hot
and he's a pig,
he kicked me out
of the Big Brother program.
So he saw the bruises up close
and did nothing.
-Then you report it
to the police.
You let them do their job.
-I did!
-[Shaw] What?
-To you!
I reported it to you!
-What are you talking about?
-They cremated him...
before I even got a chance
to see him.
They said he killed himself...
but we both know
that's not what happened.
-What happened?
-He died...in his last fight.
He was killed...
and then they
covered their tracks
by burning his body and
putting him in a fucking box.
They didn't even
give me an urn.
They gave me a fucking shoebox!
-AJ, I'm running out of time.
I did everything
you asked me to do.
Where's my kid?
-Well, he deserved better.
-Where's my kid?
-So tell me, Shaw--
-I did everything
you asked me to do. Come on.
-Would you be satisfied
if this was Aaron's grave?
Would you be satisfied?
[gun fired]
-[grunting]
God damn it! Son of a bitch!
[grunts] No, no, no!
[gun fired]
[grunting]
Why are you doing this to me?
-You failed us!
-How did I fail you?
-Think, Shaw!
-Think about what?
-Think back five years ago.
I came to you.
I told you about
the foster home.
I told you about the fighting.
Think.
-[panting]
-Shaw.
-Oh, hey, Deacon.
What's up?
-Yeah, um, what was all that?
-What? Oh, that kid?
-Yeah.
-I--I don't know.
He said something about
some bad stuff happening
over at the foster home
on Collins.
Something state-sponsored,
underground fighting
or something.
-Let me guess, kid's name is AJ.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. AJ.
You know him?
Maybe we should go over there
and check it out.
-Look, we've been out there
half a dozen times.
There's nothing there.
But I'll look into it.
-Okay. Well, are you sure
you don't want my help?
-Nah, I'll handle it.
-Okay. One less thing
I gotta do.
-Yeah, all right.
-All right. See ya.
I handed it off to Deacon.
-I didn't go to Deacon.
I came to you.
-He told me he handled it.
-You neglected us
just like everyone else.
-I should have
handled it myself.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
[wind blowing]
-You're...you're the
first person to apologize.
-Look, if I--if I could change
the system, I would.
I really would.
-[AJ]
I really hope you mean that.
[sirens wailing]
[dramatic music]
Before I go,
I have one more clue for you.
-No. No. Where's my son?
[sirens wailing]
-They always told us this
would be the last house
on the block for us.
-What are you--
what are you doing?
Hey.
[dramatic music]
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
-I think it's time
I see my brother.
-AJ, no. No! No!
-[Keyes] He's got a gun!
-AJ, stop!
Please. Wait!
The gun's empty!
It's empty!
-Put the gun down right now!
-Don't shoot him!
Don't shoot him!
[rapid gunfire]
No, no!
[panting hard]
No, no, no, no!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
It was empty!
-What?
-Hey, hey, hey.
Don't you go dying.
Listen to me.
Hey. I played your game.
I did what you told me to do.
Now where is he?
Come on, where is he?
-The last house on the block.
-Last house?
-Last house on the block.
The Johnson house,
the abandoned one.
-[Shaw groaning, panting]
Aaron!
[groaning]
[suspenseful music]
Aaron! Aaron!
Aaron!
-I'm so sorry, Matt.
We're too late.
-No.
-[Keyes] He's gone.
-No, he's... [panting]
[dramatic music]
Come on.
It's gotta be it.
He's got to be in here.
Dig, dig! [straining]
We're coming in!
Grab that shovel.
Come on, Aaron! Aaron!
[straining]
Hang on, Aaron.
[box thuds]
There it is.
[distant siren wailing]
Get that paramedic in here.
[panting]
Aaron? Aaron.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
[panting]
Get him out!
One, two, three!
All right.
I got you. I got you.
[straining]
Come on, get him oxygen!
Come on.
[straining] Come on.
Come on. Come on, Aaron!
Come on, buddy!
[straining] Come on.
-[coughs]
Dad.
-Yeah, yeah.
-Dad.
[sobbing]
-You're all right, buddy.
You're going to be all right.
[uplifting music]
Okay. They're gonna take you
to the hospital, all right?
I'll be right behind you, okay?
I'll be right behind you, kid.
All right?
All right, I'll see you there.
Get in.
All right.
[siren wailing]
Can I use your phone?
Thanks.
-[Mandy] Hello?
-Hey, Mandy. It's me.
-[Mandy]
Oh my God, did you find him?
-Yeah.
- -[Mandy] Yeah.
-We got him back.
We got him back.
All right, meet me
at the hospital.
[gentle music]
[birds chirping]
So I'm going to pick you up
from school at 2:30,
and Mom will pick you up
from here at four.
-Dad, I'll be fine.
-I know, but I'm still your dad
and I still worry about you.
-He can't hurt us anymore.
-I know.
-[Aaron] Yeah.
-What is this?
-Chocolate muffin.
Have some. Maybe the banana--
-Your coach approve of that?
Have an orange.
-[laughs]
-Hey!
-All right,
all right, all right.
-Welcome back, Detective.
Miss us?
-Uh, well, yeah, except
for Larry over here.
[laughter]
Missed the rest of you though.
Good to see you though.
-Take care.
-All right.
Hey, come here for a second.
Yeah.
So, um, I've had a lot of time
to think about this,
and we know that Deacon
was involved.
-We're still doing this?
-Listen, Sloan said something.
He said that this thing
is bigger than either of us.
-We're still doing this.
Okay, what does that mean?
-AJ mentioned that the man
that would make him fight,
they only knew him
as the great donor,
which makes me think we
just need to follow the money.
-You need a driver?
-Yeah. Let's go.
[dramatic, tense music]
-Oh, hey. I know you.
You've been all over the news.
What can I do for y'all?
-Yeah, we're here about one
of your donors.
-Oh?
-We need to access
your donor database.
We're doing some follow-ups
after a recent case.
-Oh yes, that's been all
over the news too,
and not in a good way.
Giving Clinton
a total bum rap.
-Where can we find
that database?
-That would be Mrs. Richards.
She handles all that for us.
-The mayor's wife?
-The one and only.
She and her husband do
a lot of good work for Clinton
and the foster care system,
but that doesn't seem
to make the news.
Anyway, her office
is right over there.
He's kind of cute.
-[Keyes] Thank you.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
[knock on door]
-Mrs. Richards,
Hi, I'm Detective--
-Detective Shaw.
Happy to see you're okay.
You're a hero.
How's Aaron?
-He's--he's great, thank you.
Uh, this is Detective Keyes.
Mind if we have
a seat real quick?
-Please.
-Thank you.
-[Claudia]
What can I do for you?
-You know about the,
the Foster case we just worked?
We think that there may be
a connection to Jackson's death.
That's AJ's brother.
-Oh, I'm sorry,
I don't know much
of the details besides
what I've read online.
How can I help?
-We're looking
for a large monthly donation of,
I don't know, twenty,
twenty-five thousand dollars.
-Oh, well, I--I don't really
know any people that do that
besides the city.
We provide most of the funds
really just to keep
the homes afloat.
-So it comes
from the mayor's office?
-Well, technically it comes
from the state,
but my husband is
a huge supporter of foster care
and he allocates
a lot of money that way.
These children are
our future, you know?
-Mm. They sure are.
I think that's it.
Thank you.
-Anytime.
-You have that look
in your eyes.
-I got a hunch.
-What?
-I don't know yet.
Follow me.
-Oh, no, he's on a call.
You can't--
-I am the man.
That's--
-I'm sorry, sir.
They just barged in.
-That's okay, Chelsea.
I--I got to call you back.
Detective Shaw, the hero.
What can I do for you?
-Why didn't you tell me
about the man?
-The man?
-Yeah.
The man that forced foster kids
into underground fighting.
-I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
-The man. The man
who AJ and Jackson
were taken to every week
and forced to fight other kids
for his own entertainment
and financial gain.
I'm talking about you.
-Me?
-Yeah.
-Get the hell out of my office.
-We talked to your wife.
She said you've been sending
quite a bit of money
to the foster agency.
-You talked to my wife?
-Why so much money?
-Because I'm trying
to help these kids.
-Bullshit.
-Excuse me?
-I got this--this--this really
sick feeling in my stomach
last time I saw you
at the precinct.
[unnerving music]
-Man, that's not a good feeling.
-Yeah, and then I felt it again
when I saw you there
the next time.
[unnerving music]
So I did a little deeper dive,
and I found out
that Deacon and Sloan
were doing other work
paid by City Hall.
And then there were
the foster homes.
[unnerving music]
You guys would pay them
to bring you kids,
cover up the abuse,
and then you'd keep
sending them money.
-Sound about right?
-I'm gonna have your badges
for this.
-You know, I bet we'd get
some pretty quick confirmations
if we talked
to a few of these kids.
-I wonder how many
there have been.
-You think you're so smart,
the two of you, huh?
You cannot prove any of this,
and you know what's funny, Shaw,
is you were almost a hero
for a day, but now...
-You know what's really funny
is that once you know
where to look,
it's really not that hard
to find.
[unnerving music continues]
See, there are
cameras everywhere.
I could track you
right to the scene.
[unnerving music continues]
I could track you walking
into the boxing gym,
and I can track those kids
walking out
with bruises or worse.
-Technology, baby.
[smacks hard]
-I taught those kids to be men.
I taught them discipline.
-You taught them to be killers
who can't live with themselves.
I want you to think about that
while you rot in prison,
and then--and then we'll see
what kind of a man you become.
-Mayor Richard, Mayor Richard.
You're accused
of being the ringleader
of an underage fight club
with our foster youth.
What do you have to say?
-No comment.
-[reporter 1] Mr. Mayor,
over here. We got a question.
-[reporter 2] Any comment?
-[reporter 3]
Wait, wait. Mr. Mayor, wait.
What do you have to say?
-[reporter 4]
Mayor, any comment?
-Get that out of my face.
[siren wailing]
[dramatic music]
[dramatic music fades]
[door thumps]
-Are we still doing this?
-Doing what?
-Retiring.
-All right.
I'll come back,
but only part-time, all right?
I gotta be a better dad,
and somebody has
to uncover those cases
that Deacon neglected, so...
-Must be a lot.
Do you want them?
-Yeah. Yeah.
I let those kids down.
-Hey, you didn't let
anybody down.
You're the best cop I ever had.
You solved that case in one day.
That's some kind of a record.
A lot of other kids out there
sure could use your help.
Keyes came to see me yesterday.
She said she wants
these cold cases with you.
-Yeah? What about the mayor?
-He's still awaiting trial,
but they ain't
gonna go easy on him.
Not with kids involved.
-Good.
-All right. You can start
with this tomorrow.
Go to Aaron's game.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-Are you sure?
Okay. Okay.
-From one dad to another.
-[Shaw] You're the man, Haas.
-I am the man.
[door thumps]
-[newscaster] In the latest
from the underground fighting
foster care abuse case
against former
Mayor Stephen Richards,
the Clinton County DA appears
to have found her star witness,
Detective Robert Sloan,
considered one of the dirtiest
cops on the mayor's payroll.
If convicted, the former mayor
could face up to 20 years
in prison.
♪ The wind changed the first
day that you came through ♪
♪ Cut the corn,
washed it clean ♪
♪ Now everything
that's ever gone before ♪
♪ Is like a blur ♪
♪ And it's all because of you ♪
♪ And now I find this city's
like a stranger to me ♪
♪ I once was fooled
by Cadillacs and honey ♪
♪ And no one feels like you ♪
♪ Not like you ♪
-[Shaw] Hey.
-Hey. Matt.
You made it.
-I wasn't gonna miss it.
♪ A marching band
on a sunny day ♪
♪ Two pretty eyes
or a pretty face ♪
[audience cheers]
Oh, okay, okay.
It's all right, it's all right.
All right, you got it.
♪ Lay down on hard
and ancient stone ♪
[whistle blows]
[Shaw] Oh, my--
-Oh, come on.
-Did you see that?
Come on, ref!
[indistinct chatter]
All right, all right,
here we go.
All right, let's go,
come on, kids, here we go!
Come on, Aaron!
♪ You're not too late ♪
[whistle blows]
♪ And there are times I know
when I will have to chase you ♪
Yes! All right! All right!
Oh, yes!
-You didn't retire, did you?
-You know what?
I'm here. I'm here now.
-I know. It's okay.
It's who you are.
It's what you do.
It's part of why I love you.
Thank you.
-For what?
-For Aaron.
For finding him
and for saving him.
-He's my son, Mandy.
-I know.
-He's our son.
I know, I know,
but you didn't give up.
-I'd do anything for that kid.
And you.
-So I made lasagna tonight.
Do you, uh, want to join us?
[chuckles] Come on,
don't look so shocked.
We are family.
-I do miss your lasagna.
Yes, I'll be there.
Yeah.
♪ You're not too late ♪
[♪♪♪]
-[Aaron] Come on, come on.
♪ And in the forest
I made my home ♪
♪ Lay down on hard
and ancient stone ♪
♪ And if my heart
should somehow stop ♪
♪ I'll hang on to the hope ♪
♪ That you're not too late ♪
♪ And there are times I know
when I will have to chase you ♪
♪ The further from my side
you go the longing grows ♪
♪ And I will hate this,
but I'll still want you ♪
♪ Yes, I will hate it,
but I'll still want you now ♪
♪ Cause evenwhen
the flower dies ♪
♪ Something's by its side ♪
♪ A helping hand
or a kiss goodbye ♪
♪ To ease it on its way ♪
♪ In the forest I made my home ♪
♪ Lay down on hard
and ancient stone ♪
♪ And if my heart
should somehow stop ♪
♪ I'll hang on to the hope ♪
♪ That you're not too late ♪
-Hello, Mayor.
-[grunting] [groaning]
[“Bring It On” by
Dawkins Nathaniel and Erba Tom]
[washing machine whirring]
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ Do you accept the challenge? ♪
♪ I'm-a test your balance ♪
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ You can't stand the violence
(Bring it on)♪
♪ So put your tail
between your legs ♪
♪ And leave in silence ♪
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ You can't handle the heat ♪
♪ This cannibal
is hungry for meat ♪
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ And I'm ready to eat
(Bring it on) ♪
♪ So if you're scared get
outta here ♪
♪ Before you get beat ♪
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ Show me the money,
show me the glory ♪
♪ Gimme a second to demonstrate
let me tell you the story ♪
♪ Do me a favor, pretend my name
wasn't in the street ♪
♪ If you my homie you won't have
no problem holding this heat ♪
♪ If you my enemy, then
stay away you gets no love ♪
♪ lmagine your soul escaping,
just floatin' above ♪
♪ Another day, another dollar,
earned the paper real slick ♪
♪ Ah, it doesn't matter
if it's illegitimate ♪
♪ Either way we're gonna get
what we want and get it quick ♪
♪ If you in the way, you feel
the contents of this clip ♪
♪ I'm not a gangsta, but I know
gangstas belong in the dump ♪
♪ I'm not a softie, come on, let
me see you show you a chump ♪
♪ Not a little boy talkin'
big man talk, neither ♪
♪ I'm a cold brotha, never
catch me without a heater ♪
♪ You want drama, I've got it
for you like it was Broadway ♪
♪ Didn't wanna listen, now you
have to learn it the hard way ♪
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ Do you accept the challenge? ♪
♪ I'm-a test your balance ♪
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ You can't stand the violence
(Bring it on) ♪
♪ So put your tail
between your legs ♪
♪ And leave in silence ♪
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ You can't handle the heat ♪
♪ This cannibal
is hungry for meat ♪
♪ Bring it on ♪
♪ And I'm ready to eat
(Bring it on) ♪
♪ So if you're scared get
outta here ♪
♪ Before you get beat ♪
[“Maybe” by Danny Camaro]
♪ You're kind to me ♪
♪ From the darkness ♪
♪ You hail away name new ♪
♪ You saunter out
from the shadow ♪
♪ You made me feel
something new ♪
♪ Maybe one day
you'll take me away ♪